原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译
Effy17  苏小黛  yvonne
Carolgcz  米糊  kathy567
翻译
DerbyNinja  布塔  海云生
校对     布塔细思极恐
好了
All right, then.
时间轴   西·查  Ans
没有影子  啾  caroline
我们说到哪了
Where were we?
对了  想起来了
Oh, yeah, that's right. Now I remember.
后期     渔夫
"女巫二三事"
"A note about witches."
关于女巫你们得知道
See, here's the thing about them.
她们是真的
They're real!
总监     布塔
女巫千真万确存在
Witches are as real as a rock in your shoe.
这是第一件事
That's the first thing you need to know.
你们得知道的第二件事就是
The second thing you need to know,
她们就在这里
they're here!
隐匿于我们当中
And they live amongst us...
和人类共同生活
side by side, with humans.
不论是大城市  还是小乡镇
In every big city, in every small town.
谁知道呢
For all you know,
说不定你家隔壁就住着女巫
a witch might be living right next door to you right now.
她们无处不在
They everywhere!
护士可能是女巫
A witch might be a nurse,
老师也可能是
or your teacher,
你最好相信我说的
and you can bet your sweet patootie
公车上那个送你美味的盐水太妃糖的
that friendly, little old lady on the bus offering you
看似友善的小老太婆
a delicious piece of salt water taffy
也是个女巫
is a witch.
而最重要的一点
And here's the most important thing.
最重要的一点是
The most important thing.
女巫对小孩恨之入骨
Witches hate children!
女巫每时每刻
A witch spends all her time
都在思考消灭小孩的法子
thinking up ways to destroy children.
她满脑子就只有这一件事
That's all she thinks about.
"我该怎么压扁这个可恶的小孩"
"How will I squish this horrible child?"
女巫从压扁小孩当中获得的乐趣
A witch gets the same pleasure from squishing a child
正如你们吃冰淇淋所获得的欢乐一样
as you get from eating a bowl of ice cream
冰淇淋上洒满奶油糖浆
covered in butterscotch syrup,
再加点奶油
with whipped cream,
坚果碎
chopped nuts,
顶上再放颗樱桃
and a cherry on top.
我的故事始于1968年的最后一个月
My story begins during the last month of 1968.
相信吗  我曾经是个小男孩
Believe it or not, I was once a young boy.
有爸爸妈妈的小男孩
A boy with a mother and a father.
我们那时住在芝加哥
We lived in Chicago.
圣诞时分经常下雪
And it snows a lot at Christmas time.
雪最令人头疼的一点就是  它很滑
Tricky thing with snow is, it's slippery.
-去前面  这边  -妈妈
- Take the front! This way! - Mom?
-我系了安全带  -爸爸
- I was wearing my seat belt. - Dad?
妈妈
Mom!
可我爸妈没系
Mama and Daddy weren't.
妈妈  爸爸
Mama! Dad!
Mommy! Dad!
我们救你出来
Let's get you out of here.
在我八岁的圣诞节
It was during my eighth Christmas
我失去了父母
that I lost my mother and father.
我的乖孩子
My dear child...
外婆
Grandma.
外婆来了
Grandma's here.
你会没事的
You gonna be all right.
来  让我看看你
Here, let me look at you.
我带你走吧
I'mma get you out of here.
你的东西都收拾好了  我带你回家
I packed your things, I'm gonna take you home.
回家  回我家吗
Home? To my house?
不  亲爱的
No, darling.
回外婆家
Home to my house.
需要我帮你把东西拎进去吗  姐妹
Need any help bringing these bags inside, sister?
谢谢  不用了  雷吉纳德
Oh, no, thank you, Reginald.
你帮的忙够多了
You've done enough already.
在车站遇见你一定是天意
Running into you at the bus station was a godsend.
我十分感激
I'm much obliged.
乐意效劳
My pleasure.
周日教堂见吗
I'll see you in church come Sunday?
那是当然
Oh, you know you will.
很高兴认识你  年轻人
Pleasure to make your acquaintance, young man.
欢迎来到迪莫波利斯
Welcome to Demopolis.
-谢谢  雷吉  -回见
- Thank you, Reggie. - Sister.
等等
Wait.
别穿着脏鞋踩我的地毯
Take them shoes off before you walk on my good rug.
外婆是我妈妈的妈妈
Grandma was my mama's mama.
她虽强势  但心地善良
A tough lady with a big heart.
要是你犯了错
The kind that wouldn't hesitate
她会毫不手软地打你一顿
to give a spanking if you deserve it
但当你需要拥抱时  她也毫不吝啬
or a big ol' hug if you needed it.
我想着
I reckon...
你住这里正合适
you'll be comfy here.
这原来是你妈妈的房间
In your mama's old room.
我们明天再好好安顿
We'll get you situated tomorrow.
我去做点热巧克力
I'm gonna make some hot chocolate.
想喝吗
Want some?
我还是做点吧
I'm gonna make some anyway,
以防你改变主意
in case you change your mind.
明日最高气温23摄氏度
High tomorrow, 73.
小家伙  你这是干嘛
Young man, what is wrong with you?
怎么一个人孤零零坐在这里  外面天气多好呀
Sitting in here all by your lonesome. It's nice out.
想吃点东西吗
You want something to eat?
我刚炸好鸡翅
I just fried some wings.
没人能拒绝我的鸡翅  我给你端一盘来
Nobody turns down my wings. I'm gonna make you a plate.
♪ 如果你感到前路无望 ♪
♪ Now if you Feel that you can't go on ♪
♪ 所有希望都已成空 ♪
♪ Because all of your hope is gone ♪
♪ 如果你的生活充满困惑 ♪
♪ And your life is filled with much confusion ♪
♪ 连快乐都成了一种幻觉 ♪
♪ Until happiness is just an illusion ♪
♪ 如果你的世界已濒临崩塌 ♪
♪ And your world around is tumblin' down ♪
♪ 亲爱的 ♪
♪ Darlin' ♪
♪ 伸出手来 ♪
♪ Reach out ♪
来吧  宝贝  伸手
Come on, baby. Come on.
你还等什么呢
What you waiting for?
没什么胃口
Don't feel like eating.
我还不想浪费这好好的粮食呢
And I don't feel like wasting all this good food.
怎么  你觉得我应该可怜你吗
What, you think I'm supposed to feel sorry for you?
我一点也不
Well, I don't.
我难过吗  当然
Do I feel bad? Yeah.
但我不可怜你
But not sorry.
有时  上帝会以我们想不到的方式
Sometimes, whatever the good Lord needs to teach us
指引我们
comes in ways we don't see.
但这不意味着我们不能从中学到些什么
But it doesn't mean we're not supposed to learn something.
你看
Look here.
她是我的宝贝女儿
This was my baby.
只要能让她复活  我愿意付出一切代价
I'd do anything for her to be here right now.
但上帝对她另有安排
But the Man Above had another plan for her.
而对我来讲公平与否  并不重要
And whether it seems fair to me or not, it doesn't matter.
生活有时就是这么不公
Sometimes life isn't fair.
人人都迟早要面对这艰难的一课
It's a hard lesson for folks to learn
大多数人不用在如此年轻时面对
and most people don't have to learn it this young.
但你得面对
But you do.
懂了吗
You hear me?
拜托  宝贝  你得吃点东西
Come on now, baby, you got to eat something.
你喜欢蛋糕吗
You like cake?
玉米面包和蛋糕差不多
Well, corn bread is basically cake.
尝尝吧
Go on. Try it.
他叫什么
What's his name?
是她
It's a she.
她的名字就由你来取吧
Her name is something you can ponder.
你给你的小老鼠取好名字了吗
Have you come up with a name for your mouse yet?
快告诉我啊
Well, tell me.
别吊我的胃口
Don't be keeping me in suspense.
艾西
Aisy.
懒懒
Lazy?
那老鼠明明浑身都是劲
Well, that mouse is full of nothing but energy.
无休无止地在轮子里跑
She runs all the time in that wheel.
不是"懒懒"
Not "lazy."
是黛西
Daisy.
"黛西"啊
"Daisy." Oh.
我喜欢这名字
I like it.
再适合她不过了
That's a perfect name for her.
闭上眼睛  宝贝
Close your eyes, honey.
不知怎的  她做到了
And somehow, she did it.
一点一滴地
Little by little,
这扯扯  那拽拽
with a tug here and a pull there,
她带我走出了阴霾
she brought me out of my sadness.
尽管我的阴霾已被驱散
But even though my own darkness was being lifted,
可附近还有另一个黑影逼近
there was another dark shadow looming nearby.
非常近
Very nearby.
我当时还没意识到
I didn't know it,
但我即将第一次见到女巫
but I was about to meet my first witch.
真该死
Curses.
雷蒙德
Raymond.
这能叫新鲜吗
You call these fresh?
-可我们才进的货  -什么时候  去年吗
- But we just got them in. - When? Last year?
你看这叶子都发黄了
Look at how yellow they are.
边上还有小黑点
And those brown spots around the edges.
我才不要把上好的肉汁浪费在
I'm not gonna waste good bacon drippings
这些蔫了的菜叶上
on these shriveled-up weeds.
你能给我拿点新鲜甘蓝来吗
Can you get me some fresh greens if you don't mind?
好的  女士
Yes, ma'am.
我去看看库房里有没有
I'll see what we have in the back.
赶紧去吧
You do that.
外婆  我能买这盒钉子给黛西做个房子吗
Grandma, can I get these nails to make Daisy a house?
这种没镀锌
Well, these aren't galvanized.
得用镀锌的钉子才不会生锈
You have to use galvanized nails so they won't rust.
-可是镀锌的要多花三毛五  -安全第一
- But galvanized costs 35 cents more. - Safety first.
好的  外婆
Yes, ma'am.
要是被生锈的钉子划伤  你可能会得破伤风
You cut yourself on a rusty nail, you can get lockjaw.
-好的  外婆  -那我就得帮你治病了
- Yes, ma'am. - And then I'd have to flush out your system
要用上橄榄油  大蒜汁和塔巴斯科辣椒酱
with liver oil, garlic juice, Tabasco sauce.
你可不想尝试那些吧
You wouldn't want to go through that now, would you?
不想  外婆
No, ma'am.
很好  记住  安全第一
Good. Remember, safety first.
外婆知道如何治疗各种病痛
Grandma knew how to fix all kinds of ailments.
她跟她的外婆学会了使用草药和药水
She learned from her grandma how to use herbs and potions
还有奇怪的咒语
and strange incantations
能让病人焕然一新
to make sick people good as new.
外婆是土生土长的阿拉巴马州人
Here in Alabama, where she grew up,
她在本地是个出名的疗愈师
Grandma was known as a healer.
镀锌的
Galvanized.
小子
Boy.
你喜欢糖果吗
Do you like sweets?
她很温顺的
She is tame.
很乖的
Very sweet.
亲亲她
Give her a kiss.
小伙子
Young man.
你要想买钉子就赶紧...
You want those nails, you better come on...
很好  雷蒙德  这才像话
Yes, Raymond, that's more like it.
-外婆  我得告诉你一件事  -现在不行  孩子
- Grandma, I need to tell you something! - Not now, son.
可是  外婆...
But, Grandma...
你不是想买钉子吗
I thought you wanted those nails.
别管钉子了  我们走吧
Forget it. Let's just go.
嗯
Yeah.
咱们走吧
Let's just go.
孩子
Son,
今天上午在杂货店
what were you trying to tell me
你想跟我说什么来着
in the grocery store this morning?
你当时抖得像筛糠一样
You were shaking like a leaf.
没事了  外婆
Don't worry about that, Grandma.
-我只希望你能好起来  -我挺好的
- I just want you to feel better. - I feel fine.
告诉我你早上想说什么吧
You just tell me what you were trying to say.
当时感觉你都快抓狂了
Looked like you were about to have a conniption fit.
我不确定我看到了什么
I don't know what I saw.
有个很吓人的女士
It was a scary lady.
她叫住了我
She called to me.
可是她叫我和说话的时候
But when she did, when she talked,
她的嘴...
her mouth...
她是不是戴着手套
Was she wearing gloves?
长长的手套  一直戴到手肘
Long ones, up to her elbows?
她是不是戴着帽子
Was she wearing a hat?
她头上像是裹着毛巾之类的东西
It looked like she had a towel on her head or something.
她说话的时候
And when she talked,
声音是不是难听又嘶哑
did her voice sound ugly and scratchy
就像生锈的门在嘎吱作响
like an outhouse door swinging on a rusty hinge?
真是怕什么来什么
I feared this was happening.
你在杂货店看到的女士不是什么女士
That lady you saw in the grocery store was no lady.
你看到的
What you saw
是个女巫
was a witch.
女巫
A witch?
没错
That's right.
一个一无是处  肮脏卑鄙  阴险鬼祟的女巫
A no-good, rotten, low-down, sneaky, sneaky witch.
慢点  慢点
Okay. Okay.
你是不是和教会的朋友联合起来开我的玩笑
Is this you and your church friends trying to play a joke on me?
如果是的话  真不怎么好笑
'Cause if it is, it's not very funny.
听好了  孩子
Listen, child.
女巫可不是拿来开玩笑的
Witches ain't nothing to joke about.
我知道一些孩子现在已经不再是孩子了
I've known children who no longer exist as children on this earth.
他们被转化了
They were turned,
变形了
transformed,
被女巫带走了
taken by witches.
我可以给你讲讲爱丽丝·布鲁的事
I can tell you about Alice Blue.
爱丽丝·布鲁当年是我最好的朋友
Well, Alice Blue and I were best friends.
我们两家之间只隔一条街
We lived across the street from each other.
我们就像姐妹  密不可分
We were like sisters. Inseparable.
我们干什么都在一起  哪怕是家务活
We did everything together, even our chores.
但爱丽丝是个很磨蹭的人
But Alice was a lollygagger.
爱丽丝  别磨磨蹭蹭的了
Alice, quit lollygagging, girl.
快到晚饭时间了
It's almost suppertime.
爱丽丝做了一件小孩子绝不该做的事
Alice did something no child should ever do.
她收下了一个陌生人给的糖果
She took candy from a stranger.
我吓坏了  我像脚底抹了油一般逃了
I got so scared, I tore out of there like greased lightning,
径直跑回了家
and hightailed it straight home.
我真不该撇下爱丽丝
I never should have left Alice alone.
我知道我不该那样
I knew I shouldn't have.
可我太害怕了
But I was so scared.
到了晚上
Later that night,
当我见到爱丽丝还活着时
when I saw Alice alive,
我高兴得就像找到了一整桶奶酪的小老鼠
I was as happy as a mouse in a bucket of cheese.
但第二天一早
But the very next morning,
高兴的心情都消失了  因为那件事发生了
all that happiness went away because it happened.
她开始转化了
She started turning.
爱丽丝变鸡了  变成了鸡
Alice was chicken-afied. Chicken-alified.
我的天
Lordy!
这鸡可真大
Look at the size of that chicken.
你看到爱丽丝跑哪去了吗
Y'all seen where Alice run off to?
她就在...
She's right...
你眼前
there.
你说什么呢  孩子
What you talking about, child?
她去哪了
Where'd she go?
我努力解释我看到的事
I tried to explain what I saw,
但人人都像看疯子一样看着我
but everybody was looking at me like I was crazy.
最终  我闭上了嘴
Finally, I just shut up about it.
不过  我争取每天都去鸡圈看看她
Although, I made it a point to visit Alice in her coop every day.
你好  爱丽丝
Hi, Alice.
爱丽丝甚至会下蛋
Alice even laid eggs.
绿色的大鸡蛋
Big green ones.
是我见过最大的蛋
Biggest green eggs I ever seen.
大家说她的蛋很好吃
People said they were delicious.
那女巫呢
What about the witch?
女巫怎么了
What about her?
她离开了吗
Did she go away?
天啊  没有
Oh, my, no.
女巫一旦进入你的生活  就永远...
Once a witch come into your life, it never...
永远不会...
Never...
天啊  我的上帝
Oh, my, Lord in Heaven.
我在想什么呢
What am I thinking?
我刚说了我们今天遇到了一个女巫
I just told you we saw a witch today.
有个女巫在杂货店
A witch in the grocery store.
而我在做什么  坐在这里
And what am I doing? Sitting here
就像瞎了一只眼  另一只眼也跟着不好使了一样
like I'm blind in one eye and can't see out the other,
浪费宝贵的时间磨磨蹭蹭
wasting precious time lollygagging.
我一直好奇外婆在那个上锁的储藏室里藏了什么
Always wondered what Grandma kept in that locked closet.
结果发现里面全是医用草药和药剂
Turns out it was full of medicinal herbs and elixirs,
还有关于古老疗愈法的书
and old books about ancient healing.
我妈妈总说
Now, my mom always said
外婆算是那种乡下的赤脚大仙
Grandma was sort of a country-type healer.
但我现在开始觉得
But now I was starting to think
她可能是伏都教女祭司
she might be a voodoo priestess.
孩子  我们得走了
Child, we need to leave.
-走  -没错  离开
- Leave? - That's right, leave.
我们在这里不安全
It's not safe for us here.
可我们要去哪
But where we gonna go?
我要联系我的表亲  埃斯顿
I'll call my cousin, Eston.
让他给我们
Have him make a reservation for us
在奥尔良帝国岛大酒店订一间房
at the Grand Orleans Imperial Island Hotel.
他在那当了三十多年的厨师长
He was the executive chef there for over 30 years.
他有影响力
He's got pull there.
他是个明星
He's a star.
他做的菜让那家酒店成了知名地标
His cooking put that hotel on the map.
成了全阿拉巴马州最奢华时髦的度假胜地
It's the swankiest resort in all of Alabama.
以后你会跟自己的孙子们讲起在酒店的经历
You'll be telling your grandkids about your stay in this hotel.
你怎么知道我们在那里就安全
How do you know we'll be safe there?
因为啊  孩子
Because, child,
只有富裕的白人
ain't nothing but rich white folks
才会去住奥尔良帝国岛大酒店
at the Grand Orleans Imperial Island Hotel.
而女巫只会捕猎穷人
And witches only prey on the poor,
那些被社会忽视的人
the overlooked,
那些她们认为即使失踪也不会有人在意的孩子们
the kids they think nobody's gonna make a fuss about if they go missing.
快去收拾行李
Go pack!
外婆  每个城市都有女巫吗
Grandma, are there witches in every city?
每个城市  每个州  每个国家
Every city, every state, every country.
每个国家都有一个秘密的女巫组织
And there's a secret society of witches in every country
叫做女巫团
called a coven.
就像女巫版的扶轮社
That's just like a Rotary Club but for witches.
她们会聚集在一起
They all get together in one place
闲聊她们对谁施了咒
and gossip about who they put spells on,
或是交换药水秘方之类的
or trade potion secrets, and whatnot.
但最重要的是
But most important,
她们从高阶女巫那里接收指令
they receive orders from the Grand High Witch.
高阶女巫
The Grand High Witch?
是的  高阶女巫
The Grand High Witch, yeah.
她统管着所有女巫
She's the ruler of them all.
强大  邪恶
All-powerful, pure evil,
毫无怜悯之心
and without a stitch of mercy.
传说她是在挪威的
Yeah. Legend has it, she was hatched
冻原上孵化出来的
on the frozen tundra of Norway.
瞧瞧这个
Now, take a look at that.
怎么  你要站在那盯着看我一整天吗
What, you just gonna stand there and stare at me all day?
需要帮忙吗
Can I help you?
帮我把行李卸下来  我去登记入住
You can unload this car while I check in to this here hotel.
好的  女士
Yes, ma'am.
这是车钥匙
Here's the key.
还有
Oh, and...
不必了
No.
留着您的钱吧  女士
You keep your money, ma'am.
祝您入住愉快
And enjoy yourself.
我会的
I think I will.
外婆对这家酒店的描述是对的
Grandma was right about this hotel.
它确实很豪华
It sure was fancy.
为了摆脱那个女巫
She brought us to the Gulf of Mexico
她带我们来到了墨西哥湾
to get away from that witch.
但她绝不会想到我们即将经历什么
But she had no idea what we were about to step into.
小心你的老鼠
Be careful with the mouse.
-不行  -看在上帝的份上  你也太不讲道理了
- No. - For God's sake, i think you're being extremely unreasonable.
不行  黛德丽  我最后说一遍
No, Deidre. For the last time,
我不会让那个女人进我的房子的
I will not have that woman in my house.
-她是个很好的伙伴  -绝不可能  黛德丽
- Oh, she's very good company. - Absolutely not, Deidre.
我的天啊
Oh, for God's sake,
布鲁诺  你的脸
Bruno, your face.
真是哪里都不能带你去
Obviously can't take you anywhere.
您的房门钥匙  女士
Here you are, ma'am.
欢迎防止虐待儿童国际协会成员莅临
来吧  我们拿到钥匙了
Come on, we got our key.
我们住766号房间
We are in room 766.
听上去是个好房间
Sounds like a good room.
你还好吗  外婆
You okay, Grandma?
这是我们离开家后你第一次咳嗽
That's the first time you coughed since we left the house.
需要帮助吗  女士
Can I help you, madam?
你一定是埃斯顿的表亲了
Oh! You must be Eston's cousins.
是的  他坚持让你住766号房间
Yes, he insisted that you stay in room 766.
那是木兰套间
That's the Magnolia.
我们最好的普通套房之一
This is one of our most lovely junior suites.
你可真是个幸运的家伙  对吧
And aren't you a lucky fella? Hmm?
不是每天
It's not every day
都有像你这样的年轻人
that a young gentleman such as yourself is fortunate
能幸运地住进这么高级的酒店
to come and stay in such a fine hotel as this now, is it?
走吧  盖茨比
Come on, Gatsby.
我们走
Let's go.
去找我们的房间吧
Let's go find our room.
要我带您去吗
Would you like me to show you?
在四楼
It's on the fourth floor.
外婆  如果我们住在四楼
Grandma, if we're on the fourth floor,
为什么房间号是766
why is it number 7-6-6?
因为建酒店的人是个数字命理学家
Because the man who built this hotel was a numerologist.
他相信数字是有意义的
He believed numbers have meaning.
我对数字也略知一二
I know a little something about numbers.
七和六在一起意味着考验即将来临
Seven and six together means a test is coming.
两个六一起意味着充裕
Two sixes mean abundance.
看起来  一场大考验将会到来
So, it look like a big test might be coming.
欢迎防止虐待儿童国际协会的成员莅临
欢迎光临
Well, hello there.
奥尔良帝国岛大酒店
The Grand Orleans Imperial Island Hotel
欢迎您和您同行的捐助者们
welcomes you and your lovely group of benefactresses.
我想说我们十分赞赏您们
Uh, I would just like to say that we applaud
不胜枚举  仁慈高尚的
your innumerable, uh, philanthropic...
善举  还有...
acts and, um...
还有...
And, um...
对不起  女士
I'm sorry, madam,
但我们酒店有非常严格的禁养宠物规定
but the hotel has a very strict no-pet policy.
你看起来懂得
You seem like the sort of man
欣赏我的宝贝
who loves a precious.
不是吗  这位...
Don't you, Mister...
斯特林格  R·J·斯特林格三世  酒店经理
Stringer. R. J. Stringer III. Hotel Manager.
谢谢你为我们破例
Thank you for making an exception,
-R·J  -斯特林格
- Mr. R. J. - Stringer.
-但我还没有...没有同意  -酒店经理先生
- Yes, but I haven't yet... But I didn't agree... -Hotel manager.
那么  跟我说说
So, tell me something, Mister...
-斯特林伊先生  -斯特林格
- Stringy? - Stringer.
酒店人
Hotel man.
-经理  -三世
- Manager. - The third.
-是的  -我知道你喜欢猫咪
- Yeah. - I know you love kitties.
但你觉得
But what do you think of...
老鼠怎么样
mice?
老鼠
Mice?
是的  老鼠
Yeah. Mice.
如果这个酒店里有到处乱跑的老鼠
What would you do if there were mice
你会怎么办
running all around in this hotel?
我可以向你保证  女士
Well, I can assure you, madam,
这里永远都不会有老鼠
there would never be any mice...
但如果有呢  假设有的话
But if there were? Hypothetically?
假设有的话
Oh, hypothetically.
好吧  我想我会...
Yes, I suppose, well, I would, uh...
我会打电话给灭鼠公司
I would call the exterminator.
说得没错
Exactly!
听到了吗  姐妹们
You see, girls?
他会打电话给灭鼠公司
He would call the exterminator!
像所有头脑正常的人类一样
Just like any normal human with his head screwed on right,
他会消灭那些小鬼
he would exterminate those brats.
是老鼠
Uh... Rats.
我们会消灭老鼠
We would exterminate the rats.
邪恶
Evil.
没有别的词可以形容她们了
There's no other way to describe them.
纯粹的  毫不掩饰的邪恶
Pure, unvarnished evil.
这就是女巫
That's what witches are.
你知道我总是咳嗽吧
Now, you see this here cough of mine?
有可能就是女巫害的
It was likely brought on by a witch.
可能就是你在杂货店看到的那个
Probably that one you saw in the grocery store.
真的吗  女巫可以让你咳嗽吗
Really? A witch can make you cough?
当然可以  你最好相信我说的
Oh, you bet your sweet patootie they can.
外婆  怎么区分真正的女巫和普通的女人呢
Grandma, how can you tell a real witch from a normal lady?
首先  女巫根本不是真的女人
Well, first of all, witches aren't really women at all.
她们是化成人形的恶魔
They're demons in human shape.
所以如果你仔细观察女巫
That's why if you look closely at a witch,
就会发现她的嘴角很长
you'll notice the corners of her mouth is elongated,
几乎延伸到她的耳朵
stretching almost up to her ears,
通常还用浓妆加以遮盖
and that's usually hidden with pancake makeup.
真正的女巫总是戴着手套  从来不摘
And a real witch always wears gloves. Always.
因为真正的女巫是没有手的
Because a real witch doesn't have hands.
只有爪子
She's got claws.
爪子
Claws?
她们也没有脚趾
And they don't have toes.
她们丑陋的脚像是
Their ugly feet look like
所有脚趾都被斧头砍下来了
their toes got chopped off with an axe.
所有的女巫都是光头
And all witches are bald.
脑袋像光溜溜的煮鸡蛋
As bald as a boiled egg.
所以她们戴假发
So, they wear wigs.
这会让她们长可怕的疮
And it gives them nasty sores.
"假发疹"  女巫们是这么叫的
"Wig rash," The witches call it.
让她们很难受得要命
And it makes them crazy.
所以  手套
So, gloves,
假发
wigs.
这就是全部了吗
Is that everything?
鼻洞
Nose-holes.
-鼻洞  -是的  鼻孔
- Nose-holes? - Yeah. Nostrils.
鼻洞
Nose-holes.
女巫的鼻洞比正常人的大
Witches have larger nose-holes than normal people.
当她们想要嗅出一个孩子时
When they need to sniff out a child,
这些鼻洞就会扩大
those nose-holes can grow out
直径可达到20厘米
as big as eight inches in diameter.
但记住  女巫觉得小孩很臭
But, mind you, children smell horrible to witches.
刚洗过澡的小孩也是吗
Even if the kid just had a bath?
那就更臭了
That makes it worse.
刚洗干净的小孩对女巫来说闻起来像狗屎
A freshly clean kid smells like dog poop to a witch.
-狗屎  -没错
- Dog poop? - That's right.
小孩越干净
And the cleaner the kid,
对女巫来说就越难闻
the poopier he smells to a witch.
也许我该停止洗澡了
Maybe I should stop taking baths.
孩子  别惹我生气
Child, don't test me.
女巫能在我们睡觉的时候进来抓我们吗
Can a witch come in here and get us while we sleep?
不
No.
完全不会
Not at all.
女巫从不做傻事
Witches never do silly things like
像爬排水管或者闯进别人家里
climbing drainpipes or breaking into people's houses.
而且  她们也不知道我们在哪
Besides, they have no idea where we are.
好吧  但我还是有点害怕
Okay, but I'm still a little scared.
过来吧  来这里  小家伙
Over here, come on, little man.
来吧
There we go.
好好睡一觉
Get some sleep.
是吗
Really?
第二天早上
The next morning,
阳光明媚  空气清新
the sun was shining and the air was crispy clear.
我安静无声  好让外婆可以睡觉
I kept quiet as a mouse so Grandma could sleep in,
我自己做了决定
and I took it upon myself
给她点了客房早餐
to order her some room service breakfast.
早餐来了  外婆
Here's your breakfast, Grandma.
炒鸡蛋  乡村炸牛排
Scrambled eggs, chicken fried steak,
玉米粗粉  山核桃卷
hominy grits, pecan sticky buns,
大黄草莓酱
rhubarb strawberry jam,
一壶薄荷甜冰茶
and a pitcher of sweet iced tea with mint.
闻起来真特别
That sure smells special.
天呐  我起太晚了
Mercy, I slept in late.
谢谢你给我点了早餐  亲爱的
Well, thank you for ordering me breakfast, darling.
我给了客房服务员五毛钱小费
I gave the room service guy a half a dollar tip.
可以吗
Was that okay?
你真有绅士风度
That's mighty gentlemanly of you.
外婆  你没事吧
Grandma, are you okay?
我没事  就是喉咙有点痒
I'm fine. Just a little tickle.
把那杯茶递给外婆吧
Grab Grandma that glass of tea.
听着  外婆今天要休息一下
And listen, Grandma's gonna take it easy today.
但我想你出去外面转一转
But I want you to get outside and run around.
去海边看看  好好玩玩
Go down to the water. Have fun.
我在想我可以去训练黛西
I was thinking I would do some training with Daisy.
带她一起去
Well, take her with.
只是别让她太靠近海边
Just don't let her get too close to the water.
我可不想让那些大海蛇抓到她
I wouldn't want some big old sea snake to grab ahold of her.
海蛇
Sea snake?
我逗你的  根本没有什么海蛇
I'm just joshing. There ain't no sea snakes.
你去吧  玩得开心
You go on now. Have fun.
别担心我  我没事
And don't worry about me. I'm fine.
虽然我知道外婆说有海蛇是开玩笑的
Even though I knew grandma was kidding about the sea snakes,
但是我不想冒险
I didn't wanna take any chances,
所以我们没出去
so we stayed inside.
可是没想到
And wouldn't you know,
我们走到了一个大宴会厅
we came upon the big ballroom where it turns out
防止虐待儿童国际协会的人
the International Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children folks
要在那里开会
were gonna have their conference.
那边的
You there!
你在做什么
And what are you doing?
非法闯入吗
Breaking and entering?
想找一个安静的地方
Looking for a quiet spot.
做什么
For what?
训练
Training.
训练什么
Training what?
真不错  他叫什么
Cool. Super. What's his name?
是她  她叫黛西
It's a she. And her name is Daisy.
我能抱抱她吗
Can I hold her?
她不太喜欢陌生人
She's not too comfortable around strangers.
她会什么特技吗
Can she do any tricks or anything?
我们正准备开始训练
We were just about to do some training.
想看看吗
Wanna watch?
现在几点了
What time is it?
有位亲切的女士叫我12点25分在这里见她
A nice lady told me to meet her here at 12:25.
她说她会给我六块瑞士巧克力
She said she would give me six bars of Swiss chocolate.
你叫什么名字  我叫...
What's your name? I'm...
布鲁诺·詹金斯
Bruno Jenkins!
我到处在找你  小伙子
I've been looking for you everywhere, young man.
你爸爸很生气
Your father is furious.
妈妈  你好
Hello, Mother.
这是我的新朋友
This is my new friend.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
看看你的手  脏死了
Look at your hands, they're filthy!
看看你的衣服  简直一团糟
Look at your shirt! It's a complete mess!
跟我走
Come with me.
你都做了什么
What have you been doing?
在香肠厂里跑来跑去吗
Running around in a sausage factory?
大厅里一个人都没有
The room was completely empty.
正是我和黛西训练的最佳场所
A perfect place for me and Daisy to do our training.
而且我想
And I figured,
如果防止虐待儿童国际协会的人来了
if all the Prevention of Cruelty to Children people showed up,
他们大概也不会责备一个
they would probably look kindly on a young mouse trainer
忙自己的事的年轻驯鼠师
who was just going about his business.
天呐  吓死我了
Jeez, that scared the crap out of me.
我们到了
So, here we are.
这就是皇家大宴会厅
Here is the Le Grand Imperial Ballroom
或是我们所说的沙龙大展厅
or Le Salon Grande, as we call it.
其实我们管这里叫壁画厅
Well, actually we call it the Mural Room
因为这些美丽的壁画...
because of all these beautiful murals...
我听说这里只有一扇门进出是吗
I was told there is only one door in and out, yeah?
是的
Yeah. Yes.
只有这一扇门进出
There's, only that door there, in and out,
当然了
and which, of course,
消防局局长对此很不满意
does not make the fire marshal very happy.
所以你们可别点火
So, don't you go starting any fires.
这间大厅可以
This room will do.
好的
Right, so...
如果女士们有任何需要的话
Yeah, so, if there's any... Is there anything else that you ladies...
不需要
No.
-不需要吗  -再见
- No? - Bye-bye.
好吧
All right.
西尔莎  把门锁上
Saoirse, secure the room!
你们这些假扮的女士们
Okay, you so-called ladies.
准备解除伪装
Prepare for removal.
醒醒
Wake up.
你们这些满身束缚的女妖
Okay, you trussed-up succubines,
准许摘掉手套
you may remove your gloves.
准许脱掉鞋子
You may remove your shoes.
然后
And...
准许摘掉假发
you may remove your wigs!
她们全都是女巫
They're all witches.
我真的害怕了  吓得浑身发冷
My blood ran cold as I started to get real scared.
我被困在一个满是秃头女巫的大厅里了
Here I was, trapped in a room with a bunch of bald-headed witches!
那个凶狠的光头老大
And the mean one, the bald-head honcho
就站在我的上方
who was standing right above me,
下达各种命令
the one who was giving all the orders,
我一看清她的样子
as soon as I got a good look at her,
立刻就知道她是谁了
I knew instantly who she had to be.
她是高阶女巫
She's the Grand High Witch.
女巫们
Witches.
你们就是一群废物
You are a heap of good-for-nothing worms!
今早
This morning,
我在吃早餐
I'm having my breakfast
从窗户望出去  望着海滩
and I'm looking out the window, at the beach,
我看到了什么
and what am I seeing?
What am I seeing?
我看到了几十个
I'm seeing dozens...
我看到了几百个
I'm seeing hundreds...
我看到成百上千个讨厌的小鬼
I'm seeing hundreds of repulsive little brats
在沙滩上玩耍
playing in the sand,
这让我顿时没了食欲
and it's putting me right off my food!
所以
So...
我的命令如下
Here are my orders.
你们要把世界上每一个小孩
I want every child in the world...
都消灭掉
rubbed out!
压扁  挤爆  碾碎
Squashed, squirted, and frittered!
大人  您有什么计划吗
Your Excellency, do you have a plan?
我们怎么可能消灭所有的孩子呢
How can we possibly wipe out every child?
这其实是个好问题
That was actually a good question.
虽然违抗上级  但是个好问题
Insubordinate but a good question.
我当然有计划
Of course I have a plan.
我要你们都回到自己可悲的小镇上
I want each of you to return to your pathetic little town.
去开一家
And open...
糖果店
a candy store.
在这家店里
And in this store
你们只卖最高档  最美味的糖果
you will sell only the highest quality, tastiest candy.
你们也许在想
Now, you're probably wondering,
我哪里有钱开糖果店呢
"Where do I get the money to buy a candy shop?"
这个问题我也想过了
Well, I have thought of that too.
在我的房间里  666号房间
In my room, room number 666,
我有个箱子  里面装满了崭新的百元大钞
I have a steamer trunk filled with brand-new, crisp $100 bills!
666号房间
Room 666.
记住  666号房间
Remember that room number 666
你们的店里
and your shops will sell
只卖最高档  最美味的糖果
only the highest quality, tastiest candy.
然后
And...
我们用86号配方
We use Formula Number 86
慢性变鼠剂
Delayed Action Mouse Maker!
一颗糖果加一滴变鼠剂
One drop of Mouse Maker in a piece of candy
能让一个肮脏的小孩
will transform a dirty little child
在一小时后变成老鼠
into a mouse in one hour!
加两滴
Two drops
能让恶心的小鬼在30后变成老鼠
will transform the disgusting little brat in 30 minutes.
加三滴  则立即生效
And three drops is instantaneous.
立即变成老鼠
An instant mouse!
过奖了
No, no, no.
都停下
Shut up.
那么
So,
不到一小时前
less than an hour ago,
我在大堂里发现了一个难闻的小男孩
I found a repulsive smelly little boy in the lobby
我给了他一块极其昂贵的瑞士巧克力
and I gave him an outrageously expensive bar of Swiss chocolate.
那块巧克力加了一滴
A chocolate bar that was laced with one drop
-我的86号  -不是吧
- of my Number 86... - Oh, no.
慢性变鼠剂
Delayed Action Mouse Maker potion!
布鲁诺
Bruno.
我告诉那个贪婪的小鬼
And I told the greedy little brat
12点25分来这里见我
to meet me here at 12:25.
所以  不到十分钟后
So, in less than 10 minutes,
你们这些可怜的女巫就会看到我是多么天才
all you pathetic witches will see what a true genius I am!
天才  天才  天才
Genius! Genius! Genius!
都闭嘴
Quiet!
我的巧克力在哪里
Where's my chocolate?
是那个贪婪的小白痴
It's the greedy little cretin.
快点  把你们的假发戴上
Quick! Put on your wigs!
欢迎你...
Welcome, you...
英俊帅气的小伙子
fine, handsome man.
我们正恭候大驾
We've been waiting.
宝贝
Darling boy.
这是给你的巧克力
I have your chocolate for you.
你答应给我六块巧克力
You promised me six bars of chocolate.
你手上只有一块
I only see one in your hand.
你们看  女士们
You see, ladies,
他不仅又胖又蠢  还贪得无厌
not only is he fat and stupid but greedy too.
没错  小伙子
That's right, little man.
这是你的美味巧克力
Here is your delicious chocolate.
过来拿  过来拿
Come and get it. Come and get it.
准备好了  姐妹们
Get ready, girls.
倒数十秒
Ten seconds.
把巧克力给我  给我
Give me my chocolate. Give it to me.
就在这  亲爱的
It's right here, my darling.
黛西  我们该怎么办
Daisy, what do we do?
给我  给我
Give me. Give me.
倒数五秒
Five seconds.
把巧克力给我  给我
Give me my chocolate. Give it to me.
三
Three...
-给我  给我  给我  -二
- Give me it. Give me. Give me! - Two...
一
One...
开始
Ignition!
那个臭小鬼
That smelly brat,
讨厌的寄生虫
that horrid louse
变成了...
has been transformed...
她成功了  她是个天才
She's done it. She's a genius.
可爱的小老鼠
into a lovely little mouse!
你这是什么意思
What's the big idea?
我的巧克力呢
Where's my chocolate?
踩扁他
Squish him!
踩扁他  弄死他
Squish him! Kill him!
他在这里
He's right there.
她们把布鲁诺变成了一只老鼠
They turned Bruno into a mouse
现在她们要踩扁他
and now they're trying to squish him.
我去救他
I'll fetch him.
你开口说话了
Did you just talk?
是一群老鼠
It's a swarm!
到处都是
They're everywhere!
抓住他  他在哪  他在哪
Get him. Where is he? Where is he?
天啊  你是个巨人  你怎么这么大个
Gosh! You're a giant. Why are you so big?
我不大  你很小  我是正常大小
I'm not big. You're little. I'm normal.
我怎么会很小
How can I be little?
因为你是一只老鼠
Because you're a mouse.
女巫对你施了咒
A witch put a spell on you.
女巫  什么女巫
Witch? What witch?
我就知道
I knew it!
臭狗屎
Dog dropping!
-救命  -抓住他
- Help! - Grab him.
-救命  救救我  -按住他
- Help! Help me! - Hold him down.
-把他翻过来  撬开嘴巴  -救命  救命
- Flip him. Gag position. - Help! Help!
撬开他的嘴
Open his trap.
撬开
Open it.
好吧
Okay.
要是你想来这一套
That's how you wanna play,
我们就好好陪你玩
we'll play the Shakespeare way.
一滴
One drop...
两滴
Two...
发射
Blast off.
好极了  好极了
Yes! Yes!
好极了
Yes!
你真是只可爱的小老鼠
Aren't you a cute little mouse?
木槌在谁手上
Who has the mallet?
-这里  这里  -木槌给我
- Here! Here! - Get the mallet.
木槌呢
Where's the mallet?
我什么都不怕
I'm not afraid of nothing.
我抓到他了  木槌呢
I have him. Where's the mallet?
快点  给我  给我
Come on. Give it to me. Give it to me.
快跑  布鲁诺  快跑
Run, Bruno, run!
你也是老鼠
So, you're a mouse too?
我来抓你了
Now I've got you.
四条腿跑  布鲁诺
Four legs, Bruno.
四条腿
Four legs.
老鼠们  死胡同
Rats! A dead end!
快跑  布鲁诺  快跑
Run, Bruno, run!
不
No!
我的腰
Ow, my back.
我们怎么了
What happened to us?
我们怎么成了老鼠门
Why are we mouses?
-是"老鼠们"  -随便了
- "Mice." - Whatever.
这酒店里有个女巫集会
There's a convention of witches here in the hotel,
她们有一种毒药水
and they have an evil potion.
她们把药水加到了你的巧克力里
They put it in your chocolate.
我的巧克力  哎呦
My chocolate? Crikey!
她们总是在巧克力上做手脚
They always spike the chocolate.
这是标准的邪恶女巫手法
It's standard evil witch procedure.
等等  你以前也是个孩子
Wait. You were a kid too?
是女孩
A girl.
你觉得我像小山羊吗
Do I look like a baby goat to you?
不  是老鼠
Nope, a mouse.
我们该怎么办
What are we going to do?
我不想做老鼠
I don't want to be a mouse.
我喜欢做个胖乎乎的小孩
I like being a portly little kid.
是"孩子"
"Child."
随便了
Whatever.
好了  我们得找到我外婆
All right, we have to find my grandma.
她知道关于女巫的一切
She knows everything about witches.
她知道怎么办  走吧
She'll know what to do. Come on.
两份蟹肉沙拉  你们在做什么
Two crab salads. What are you doing?
看看那些好吃的
Wow, look at all that lovely food.
好了  我们这么办
Okay, here's what we do.
看到那个通风口了吗
You see that vent?
肯定是通往大堂的  我们走
I bet that'll get us to the lobby. Let's go.
捡起来  那是白松露
Pick that up. That's white truffle.
你知道白松露有多贵吗
You have any idea how much white truffle costs?
擦一擦放到酱汁里
Wipe it off and put it in the sauce.
这是什么  你管这个叫蓬松
What is this? You call that puffed?
再来几个人帮忙
Let's get some more hands in here.
现在怎么办
So, now what?
听着  我们只需要进入电梯
Look, all we need to do is make our way to the elevator,
然后到四楼去
then up to the fourth floor.
快点
Come on.
帮个忙
Hey, a little help.
哎呦
Crikey.
-快点  -这边
- Hurry up. - This way.
我刚想到一件事
I just realized something, y'all.
我们怎么够得着四楼的按钮
How exactly do we reach the button for the fourth floor?
-几楼  -四楼  谢谢
- Floor? - Four, please.
快点
Come on.
那是我的房间  766号
There's my room, 766.
这边
This way.
她听不见我们
She's never going to hear us.
门铃
A doorbell.
过来
Come on.
哎呦
Crikey!
好了  我们搭个人梯
All right. We make a human ladder.
你是说鼠梯
You mean a mouse ladder?
没错  鼠梯
Right, a mouse ladder.
我够...我够...
I got... I got...
我够着了
I got it!
救命
Help me!
要命了  别让我掉下去
Ahhh, great balls of fire, don't let me fall!
跟我来  小伙子们
Follow me, boys.
老鼠
Mice!
老鼠  老鼠
Mice! Mice!
到处都是
They everywhere!
外婆  是我
Grandma, it's me.
外婆  是我  你的外孙
Grandma, it's me, your grandson.
我的外孙
My grandson...
是你吗  孩子
Is that you, boy?
对  外婆  是我
Yes, Grandma, it's me.
真的是你
Is it really you?
真的是我
It's really me.
-怎么回事  -是高阶女巫
- What happened? - It was the Grand High Witch.
高阶女巫
The Grand High Witch?
天啊  别是高阶女巫啊
Oh, Lord, not the Grand High Witch.
是她  她把我变成了老鼠
Yes. She mouse-afied me.
这家酒店里有好多女巫
And the whole hotel is full of witches.
她们要开女巫集会还是什么的
They're having a witch convention or something.
你经历了太多  你不该承受这些的
You been through so much, you don't need this.
外婆真的非常抱歉
Grandma's so, so sorry.
外婆  请你别趴在地上了
Grandma, please get off the floor
把我放在茶几上吧
and put me on the coffee table.
-我该怎么把你放上去  -把我抱起来啊
- How do I do that? - Pick me up.
把你抱起来
Pick you up?
对  就像我抱黛西一样
Yeah, just like I pick up Daisy.
好吧
Right.
真不敢相信你变成这样了
I can't believe this happened to you.
相信我  这还不算最糟的
Believe me, things could be a lot worse.
这还不算吗
They could?
对了  外婆
Oh, Grandma, by the way,
这是我的朋友  布鲁诺·詹金斯
this is my friend, Bruno Jenkins.
他现在也成了老鼠
He's now a mouse too,
但他之前是一个胖乎乎的英国小孩
but he used to be a chubby, little English kid.
你只说第一句就够了  "这是我的朋友  布鲁诺"
You could've just stopped at, "This is my friend, Bruno."
我很遗憾  布鲁诺
I'm so sorry, Bruno.
那些可恶的坏女巫也把你变成老鼠了
Those nasty, evil witches got you too, huh?
没错  她们把我彻底变成老鼠了
Yes. They got me good and proper.
今天真是糟糕透了
It's been an awful day.
还有谁肚子饿了吗
Anybody else hungry?
黛西以前也是个小孩  女孩
Oh, and Daisy used to be a kid... A girl too.
亲爱的  你之前为什么不说呢
Why didn't you say something before, darling?
因为身为一只老鼠  说话太危险了
Because it can be very dangerous for a mouse to talk.
大多数人不理解情况  他们会被吓到
Most people don't understand and they get scared.
我那天晚上差点就说话了
I almost said something the other night
在你讲爱丽丝·布鲁的故事的时候
when you told the story about Alice Blue
你说她被变成了一只鸡
getting turned into a chicken,
但是我改变主意了
but I thought better of it.
你也是被某个邪恶的坏女巫变成老鼠的
So, some wicked, evil witch mouse-afied you.
是的  女士  四个月前
Yes, ma'am, four months ago.
就在我逃出孤儿院的那天下午
On the very same afternoon I ran away from the orphanage.
当时的情况是  一位和蔼的女士
Well, what happened was, a kind lady...
我当时以为她很和蔼
Well, I thought she was kind.
总之  她给我了一块巧克力
Anyway, she offered me a chocolate bar,
我还没反应过来就噗的一声
and before I knew it, poof!
变成老鼠了
I was transformed.
然后  说时迟那时快
Then, faster than a hot knife cuts through butter,
一个乞丐把我抓起来  卖给了宠物店
a panhandler scoops me up and sells me to a pet store
换钱给自己食物
so he could buy food.
好吃的
Yum!
我很遗憾  黛西
I'm so sorry, Daisy.
玛丽  我的本名是玛丽
Mary. Uh, my real name is Mary.
玛丽  这个名字真好听
Mary. That's a pretty name.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
你们老是说到吃的  这让我真的很饿
All this talk about food is making me really hungry.
我可以吃点葡萄吗
Can I have one of those grapes?
所以  高阶女巫
So, it was the Grand High Witch,
她就在这家酒店里
and she's in this very hotel?
我们得做点什么让你们变回来  拨乱反正
We got to do something to turn you back. Make this right.
高阶女巫的房间里有很多药水
The Grand High Witch has a room full of potion.
她打算用这些药水将全世界的孩子都变成老鼠
And she's gonna use it to turn every kid in the world into a mouse.
我们必须救他们
We have to help them.
-是谁  -酒店维修员
- Who is it? - Hotel maintenance.
快躲起来
Quick, hide.
来  跳进我的编织包里
Here. Hop in my knitting tote.
保持低调
Keep your heads down.
你好
Yes.
很抱歉打扰你  女士
I'm sorry to bother you, ma'am,
我们收到报告说  可能有鼠患
but we got a report of a possible rodent infestation.
鼠患  在这么贵的酒店里
Rodent infestation? In a hotel this expensive?
这比屠宰日的猪叫还疯狂
That's crazier than a hog on slaughter day.
是的  女士  可能只是虚惊一场
Yes, ma'am. It's probably nothing.
声称看到老鼠的那位服务员
The maid who said she saw the rodents has a tendency
她平时就有点大惊小怪
to be a bit high-strung.
但是  为了保险起见
But, to be on the safe side,
我想在房间里放几个捕鼠夹
I thought I'd lay these here traps,
-如果你不介意的话  -好的
- if you don't mind. - Okay.
我们每个房间都要放
We put them in all the rooms.
只是以防万一
Just to be safe.
是多大的老鼠  小老鼠吗
So, uh, what are they? Mice?
不是  女士
No, ma'am.
服务员说她看到了一群又大又丑的巨鼠
Maid said she saw a swarm of huge, ugly rats.
至少有十几只
At least a dozen of them.
天啊  十几只
Goodness, a dozen?
就像我说的
Well, it's like I said,
她平时就有点大惊小怪
she has a tendency to be a bit high-strung.
新鲜的威斯康星切达干酪
Fresh Wisconsin cheddar.
让老鼠们趋之若鹜
Drives them rodents plumb crazy.
它们无法拒绝如此美味
They can't resist it.
总之  如果你听见这些捕鼠夹有响动了
Anyway, you hear any of these traps start snapping,
就给我打电话
give me a call.
当然了
I sure will.
这就好
That's right.
你什么都不懂吗  葡萄对老鼠有害
Don't you know anything? Grapes can hurt a mouse.
好了  你们三个
All right, you three.
离那些捕鼠夹远点  听见了吗
You stay away from those traps, you hear?
如果我们能拿到药水的话
If we could just get our hands on some of that potion,
我也许可以逆向工程
I might be able to reverse-engineer it.
将其转换成让老鼠变回孩子的药水
Make it a potion that turns mice into children.
旅行的时候我总是带着抗魔药草和盐
I always travel with my anti-hex herbs and salts.
但是谁知道这个邪恶的坏女巫住哪呢
But whoever knows where that wicked, evil witch is.
我们知道  她住在666号房间
We do. She's in room 666.
我们听到  她让所有的女巫
We heard her tell all those witches
在晚餐后去666号房间见她
to meet her in room 666 right after dinner.
而我们住在766号房间
And we're in room 766.
666号房间就在我们楼下
Room 666 is right below us.
天啊
Good Lord!
那个邪恶的女巫就住在我们楼下
That evil sorceress is living right beneath us?
对  我们这么办
Yes. And here's what we do.
我们等高阶女巫离开房间后
We wait for the Grand High Witch to leave her room,
用外婆的毛线将我放下去
then we use Grandma's knitting wool as a rope to lower me down
放在高阶女巫房间的阳台上
to the Grand High Witch's balcony.
我去拿一瓶药水
I grab a bottle of potion,
外婆将我拉上来  然后逆转咒语
Grandma hoists me back up, she reverses the spell,
然后  我们就变回孩子了
and ta-da! We're kids again.
小伙子  你这么快就想出了计划
Young man, you think all that up just now?
灵机一动
Popped right into my head.
肮脏讨厌的小鬼
Vile, filthy brats.
你们让我想吐
You make me puke!
哈迪斯
Hades,
世风日下
it's getting so bad,
我甚至没法好好享受一杯苦艾酒
I can't even enjoy a glass of wormwood.
她就是高阶女巫没错
She's the Grand High Witch, all right.
外婆  那就是药水
Grandma, that's the potion.
她把药水放在冰块中
She's keeping it on ice.
没错  正是我们想要的
Yeah, it's exactly what we need.
哈迪斯  来
Hades, come.
我们喝茶要迟到了
We are late for tea.
下午茶时间  完美
Teatime. Perfect.
听着  我们只需要一瓶药水
Now look, all we need is one bottle of potion.
所以尽快拿到一瓶  然后赶紧回来
So, grab one as fast as you can and hurry on back.
不知道那个怪物什么时候会回来
No telling when that monster is fixing to return.
我知道你可能很害怕  宝贝
I know you're likely scared, baby.
我不害怕  外婆
I'm not scared, Grandma.
我也不知道为什么
I don't know why,
但是自从我被变成了小老鼠后
but ever since I was turned into a small mouse,
这些小事再也吓不到我了
little things don't scare me anymore.
好吧  抓紧了
Okay. Hold on tight.
难以置信
I can't believe
他们居然不让我的宝贝进餐厅
they won't let my precious into the dining room.
这家廉价的  满是蟑螂的酒店
This fleabag, roach-trap hotel
排斥我想做的一切
discriminates against everything.
钱  钱  钱
Money. Money, money, money.
哈迪斯
Hades,
为什么在这个恶心的人类世界里
why, in this disgusting human world,
做什么事都需要用到钱
do you need money for everything?
恶心的  肮脏的金钱
Disgusting, filthy lucre.
他准备好了
He's ready.
哎呀呀
Well, well, well, well.
这团毛线为什么在这里
Why is this wool here, I wonder?
你好
Hello.
我把织的东西掉到你的阳台上了
I just dropped my knitting over the balcony.
但是没关系
But it's all right.
感谢老天  我手里还捏着它的线
Thank goodness I still have a hold of it on this end.
我继续把它拉上来就好了
Well, I'm just gonna go ahead on and... And pull it on up.
不打扰你了
I'll be out of your way.
放手吧
Let go.
我认识你
I know you.
我
Me?
我可不觉得
I don't think so.
我以前见过你
I have seen you before.
我记得你的脸
I remember your face.
你可能在大堂里见过我
You mighta seen me in the lobby, maybe.
不是  不是
No, no, no, no, no.
不是在大堂里
Not in the lobby.
我记得你是...
I remember you from...
干嘛  谁啊
What? Who is it?
我是斯特林格三世
It's Mr. Stringer III,
酒店经理
Hotel Manager.
真该死
Curses!
你想让我
You want me to remove
把海滩上的孩子都赶走
the children from the beach?
把他们都赶走
I want them removed.
我...我试试看吧
Well, I'll... I'll see what I can do.
女士  我为你拿来了这个
Madam, I procured this, uh, for you today.
你可能会用得到
I thought you might like it.
是猫笼
It's a kitty carrier.
我觉得
And I thought
可以把你的猫咪朋友放进去
you could put your feline friend in there and you can
然后就可以带着它在酒店里活动
transport him all over the hotel,
包括餐厅
including the dining room.
你可以考虑一下
Thought you might like that.
好
Well,
我告诉你吧  送猫笼的先生
let me tell you something, Mister Cat-Cage-Procurer.
我永远都不会
I will never, ever
把我宝贝的猫咪放到...
allow my precious puss to be...
快看  它喜欢待在笼子里
Well, look at that. He likes it in there.
女士  我差点忘了
Madam, I almost forgot.
关于你们今晚的晚餐
Regarding your ladies' dinner this evening,
我们忘记选汤了
we have neglected to select a soup.
有两种选择
Now, there are two choices.
一种是香辣蟹肉浓汤
One is our Cajun spice crab Creole,
另一种是种植园厨房豌豆汤
and the other one is our plantation kitchen split pea.
哪种更便宜
Which one is cheaper?
女士  你一定懂得
Well, madam, I'm sure you will appreciate
新鲜蟹肉的价值  而且...
that the crab is fresh and it is...
到底是哪种
Which one?
种植园厨房豌豆汤  这个便宜
Plantation kitchen split pea. That's the one.
那我们就要豌豆汤
Then we will have the split pea soup.
好的  女士
Yes, madam.
还有
And...
汤里不加大蒜
no garlic in the soup.
不加什么
No what?
大蒜
Garlic.
不加大蒜
No garlic?
我结巴了吗
Did I stutter?
不加大蒜
No garlic.
我的姐妹们
My women,
都有食物忌口的问题
all suffer from a selective food avoidance disorder.
挑食
Picky eaters.
好的  女士  如你所愿
Yes, madam. As you wish.
我会告诉主厨的
I will inform the chef.
赶紧去吧
You do that.
我自己出去
I'll let myself out.
赶紧去吧
You do that.
我的宝贝
Well, my precious,
既然你这么喜欢待在笼子里
since you enjoy being in that cage so much,
那就别出来了
you can stay in it!
叛徒
Traitor!
变鼠剂
Mouse Maker potion.
一滴海索草油
A drop of hyssop...
少量艾蒿油
A smidgen of mugwort...
再加上
And now,
一点来自卢尔德的疗愈水
a dash of healing water, straight from Lourdes.
这是最强效的疗愈水
This is the most powerful healing water there is.
好了
Okay.
我们牵起手  低下头来
Now let's all join hands and bow our heads.
我...
Well, I'll be...
无需多说了
Not much more to say than that.
我们总得试试  孩子们
We had to try something, kids.
这个女巫的力量比我的土方子厉害得多
This witch's power is far greater than my little home remedies.
邪恶的力量
Evil power.
还很强大
And strong.
比我强大很多
Much stronger than me.
拜托别哭  外婆
Please don't cry, Grandma.
没事的
It'll be okay.
对不起  孩子们
I'm sorry, children.
不怪你  外婆
It's not your fault, Grandma.
有时候世事无常
Sometimes things just happen.
是啊
Yeah, they do.
其实我不介意当一只老鼠
I actually don't mind being a mouse.
可以和我的新朋友们整天一起玩耍
I get to hang out with my new friends all day,
再也不用上学去
don't have to go to school anymore,
连开车都不用学了
and I don't have to learn how to drive,
也就是说我永远都不会出车祸
which means I'll never get into an accident.
你这孩子  过来
Child. Come here.
外婆  你还会照顾我吗
Grandma, will you still take care of me?
即使我是一只老鼠
Even if I stay a mouse?
我当然会了  亲爱的
Of course I will, darling.
无论你是谁
Doesn't matter who you are
无论你变成什么样
or what you look like,
只要有人爱你  这都没关系
so long as somebody loves you.
而我永远都会爱你
And I always will.
那我的朋友们呢
What about my friends?
他们也可以留下来吗
Can they stay too?
当然可以
Well, of course.
只要他们愿意
If they want to,
但别忘了  他们都有亲人在思念他们
but don't forget, they all have loved ones who miss them.
我就不一定了
I'm not so sure about that.
别犯傻  他们肯定爱你
Don't be a fool. I'm sure they love you.
我妈妈觉得我笨手笨脚
My mother thinks I'm clumsy,
我爸爸抱怨我总想吃东西
and my father complains that I'm always hungry.
或许这下他们会爱上真正的你
Well, maybe this will help them love you for who you are,
而不是因为别的
not for who you ain't.
你有父母就很幸运了  布鲁诺
You're fortunate to have parents, Bruno.
有人根本没有
Some of us don't.
但我们会没事的
But we're gonna be okay.
我们有外婆
We have Grandma.
她永远都是我们的家人
And she'll always be our family.
所以我们真的很幸运
And for that we are very blessed.
但我想知道的是
But what I wanna know
我们为什么还站在这里磨磨蹭蹭
is why are we standing around here lollygagging?
我们该怎么阻止那些可怕的女巫
How are we gonna stop those horrible witches
把更多的孩子变成老鼠
from turning more children into mice?
她说得对
She's right.
我们得想办法
We got to do something.
我知道怎么办
I know what we'll do.
我带着86号变鼠剂溜进厨房里
I sneak into the kitchen with the Number 86 Mouse Maker,
再把变鼠剂倒进女巫们的豌豆汤
then I slip the potion into the witches' pea soup
把她们都变成老鼠
and turn them all into mice.
你确定吗  小家伙
Are you sure about this, little man?
这个任务听起来既危险又可怕
This sounds like it could be a very dangerous and scary mission.
相信我  外婆  我能做到
Trust me, Grandma, I can handle it.
我们到大堂酒吧会合
I'll meet you in the lobby bar.
布鲁诺和黛西知道是哪个通风口
Bruno and Daisy know which vent.
小心点  亲爱的
Be careful, darling.
我会的  外婆
I will, Grandma.
快点
Hurry up there!
豌豆汤准备好了
The pea soup is ready.
不加大蒜
No garlic.
我来盛汤  不加大蒜  主厨
I got the soup, no garlic, Chef,
马上就来
coming right up.
我的大虾呢
Where are my prawns?
这不是大虾  这是小虾
This is not a prawn, this is a shrimp.
你不懂大虾和小虾的区别吗
You don't know the difference between a shrimp and a prawn?
数数它的钳子  两个  一  二
Count the pincers. Un, deux. One, two.
可以把汤盛出来了
Let's start ladling out that soup.
你们都快点
Come on, you people.
是  主厨
Yes, Chef.
你在做什么呢
What are you doing, huh?
我在准备大虾
I'm getting the prawns ready.
别跟我说这是大虾
Don't tell me that's a prawn.
-我可是甲壳动物专家  -这就是大虾
- I'm a crustacean expert. - This is a prawn.
我已经炒大虾三十年了
I've been sauteing prawns for 30 years
我只用黄油炒
and I only use butter.
-只用黄油  -从没用过别的油
- Only butter? - Never oil.
我才不管营养学家怎么说
I don't give a damn about what nutritionists say.
他们都是糟蹋美食
They are the ruination of cuisine.
永远都用黄油  只用黄油
Always butter, butter only.
我的大虾呢
Where are my prawns?
谁能给我把大虾准备好
Who do I have to get some prawns around here?
可以把汤盛出来了
Let's start ladling out that soup.
是  主厨
Yes, Chef.
你在哭吗
Are you crying?
在我的厨房里不许哭
There's no crying in my kitchen.
主厨  这道汤需要加点大蒜
Chef, this soup needs some garlic.
绝对不许加大蒜  斯特林格说的
Absolutely no garlic. Stringer's orders.
油锅着火
Grease fire.
那边水槽下有灭火毯
We got fire blankets under those sinks.
是我的大虾烧着了吗
Are those my prawns that just exploded?
别管大虾了  随便放点小虾吧
Forget the prawn, just throw some shrimp in there.
你们这些蠢货根本不懂...
You idiots don't know how...
谁给我把快刀  让我自尽算了
Someone get me a sharp knife so that I can kill myself.
谁去联系灭鼠公司
Somebody call an exterminator.
看  那就是我父母
Look, there's my mother and father.
那就是你父母
That's your mother and father?
千真万确
As I live and breathe.
布鲁诺  我想是时候跟你父母打个招呼了
Bruno, I think it's time to say hello to your parents.
你疯了吗  就在酒吧里
Are you mad? Right here in the bar?
时不我待
There's no time like the present.
打扰了  你们是詹金斯夫妇吗
Excuse me, are you Mr. And Mrs. Jenkins?
有什么事吗
Can we help you?
恐怕我有一些
I'm afraid I have some,
关于你们的儿子布鲁诺的奇怪消息
well, strange news about your son, Bruno.
布鲁诺怎么了  他在哪里
What about Bruno? Where is he?
或许我们可以找个地方私下谈
Maybe we can go somewhere a bit more private.
私下谈  为什么要私下谈
Private? Why do we have to be private?
这件事对他来说不好解释
It's not an easy thing for him to explain.
如果我们去你们的房间  他会感到自在许多
He'd be much more comfortable we all went up to your room.
不  女士
No, no, look here, madam,
我觉得待在这里就挺好
I'm perfectly comfortable exactly where I am.
所以你要么告诉我们布鲁诺在哪里
So, either you tell me where I can find Bruno
要么就别烦我们
or you just leave us alone now.
好吧
Well...
他就在这里
got him right here.
是老鼠  老鼠
That's a mouse! A mouse!
你到底有什么毛病
What in God's name is wrong with you?
快把这只恶心的耗子扔出去
Get that filthy rodent out of here!
不不不  这就是布鲁诺
No, no, no, no. This is Bruno.
布鲁诺  说点什么啊
Bruno, say something to them.
"说点什么"  你疯了吗
"Say something"? Are you insane?
离我们远点  我要叫经理了
Get away from us before I call the manager.
别嚷嚷了  这是你儿子布鲁诺
Quit all this hollering. This is your son, Bruno.
经理  谁去把经理叫来
Manager! Someone get me the manager.
这女人把我妻子吓得半死
This woman has just scared my wife half to death.
她手提包里装着老鼠
She's walking around with rats in her handbag.
布鲁诺  你为什么不说话
Bruno, why didn't you say something?
我爸爸讨厌我边嚼东西边说话
My father hates it when I talk with my mouth full.
外婆
Grandma.
在这里
Down here.
你回来了  谢天谢地
There you are. Thank the Lord.
怎么样
So, how'd it go?
汤做好了
Soup is on.
看  豌豆汤
Look! The pea soup.
请用  没加大蒜
Here we are, garlic free.
打扰了  女士  我能跟你谈谈吗
Excuse me, madam, may I have a word with you?
请这边走
Please, this way.
这边来
Just over here.
你现在不会随身带着
You wouldn't happen to be carrying around a mouse
一只老鼠吧
on your person now, would you?
-一只老鼠  -嗯
- A mouse? - Mmm-hmm.
我为什么要随身带着一只老鼠
Why on earth would I be carrying around a mouse?
这是不是跟酒店里到处摆满的
Does this have anything to do with all the rat traps
捕鼠器有关
being set up all over this hotel?
捕鼠器
Rat traps?
这就是你的小脑瓜想出的障眼法吗
Is this your pathetic idea of a smoke screen?
找个客人来替你背黑锅
Accusing your guests of carrying around mice
掩盖这家酒店有鼠患的事实
to hide the fact that this hotel has a mouse infestation.
不是  小声点  你说什么
No... Shh. What?
我告诉你
I'll tell you this.
我花了那么多钱住这家酒店
For what this hotel is costing me,
最好别让我看见一只老鼠
I better not see a single mouse.
连一只可爱的小老鼠都不行
Not even a tiny, cute one.
没问题  女士  我真...
Yes, madam. I'm so...
我的错  对不起
My mistake. I'm sorry.
卢瑟
Luther.
请带这位女士去我们最好的位子
Would you please show this lady to our finest table?
好的  这边请
Certainly. This way.
抱歉  女士
Apologies, madam,
我只是...
I, it's just...
我们最好的位子  女士
Our finest table, madam.
谢谢你  卢瑟  我认为
Thank you, Luther. I'm sure
这个高级餐厅里最好的位子
your finest table in this lovely establishment
就是厨房旁边的这张餐桌
is this one right here next to the kitchen.
我向来喜欢坐在出口附近
I always prefer a table near the exit
方便随时开溜
so I can get out fast.
好的
Of course.
快看
Check it out.
他们喜欢喝汤
They love the soup.
您选好了吗
Have you decided?
嗯  我要一份什锦饭
Uh, yes, I think I'll have the jambalaya.
好的  要先喝点什么吗
Excellent. And would you like something to start?
那些漂亮的女士
Well, that pea soup
喝的豌豆汤看起来很不错
those fancy ladies are eating looks good.
我就要那个
I'll have that.
抱歉  豌豆汤
I'm sorry. That soup is reserved
全都被那些女士预订了
strictly for that group of lady guests only.
请听我一句
If I may,
那些客人对大蒜严重过敏
that large party suffers from a severe garlic allergy.
所以他们要求汤里不加大蒜
So, they have requested their soup be prepared garlic free.
味道很淡  几乎难以下咽
It is very bland. Practically inedible.
我明白了
I see.
听起来真恶心
That sounds disgusting.
请容我推荐香辣蟹肉浓汤
May I suggest the Cajun spice crab Creole?
这是我们的招牌菜
It's one of our signature dishes.
听起来...
Uh, sounds...
您说
Yes?
就要虾肉浓汤吧
Uh, the... The shrimp Creole will be fine.
您是说蟹肉浓汤
You mean the crab Creole?
对  对  蟹肉浓汤
Yes, yes, the crab Creole.
好的
Very good.
躲起来  有人来了
Keep your heads down, we got company.
小辫子
Pigtails.
你说什么
I'm sorry?
小辫子
Pigtails.
你扎了小辫子
You wore pigtails.
我认识你吗
Do I know you?
许多年前  在一个破败的小镇上
Many years ago, in a shabby little town.
阿拉巴马州本地一个破败的小镇
A shabby little town right here in Alabama.
你扎了小辫子
You wore pigtails.
你从我手里逃脱了
And you got away from me.
记得吗
Remember?
但我抓到了你那个讨厌的朋友
But I got that horrid little friend of yours.
记得...
Remember...
快  搭鼠梯
Quick, mouse ladder.
是你
It was you.
你就是那个转化爱丽丝的坏女巫
You were the filthy witch who turned Alice.
咳得真严重
That's a nasty...
你们在干什么
What are you doing?
外婆  快看
Grandma, look.
好样的
Attaboy.
击掌  宝贝
High five, baby!
轰轰烈烈变老鼠
That's some serious ratification.
天啊  爬到我腿上了
Oh, my God! It's on my leg!
天啊  太震撼了
Lordy, hell's a-poppin'.
过来  你这恶心的生物
Come here, you nasty critter...
把它弄下去  弄下去
Get it off! Get it off!
弄下去
Get it off!
走吧  孩子们
Come on, kids.
是时候开溜了
It's time to skedaddle.
谁去联系灭鼠公司
Somebody call the exterminator!
干得好
Good job.
看看这些药水
Look at all this potion.
孩子们  我们得把药水全都拿走
Kids, we got to grab every bottle.
外婆  那它怎么办
Hey, Grandma, what about him?
等我们走了  我打电话让经理把它放出来
I'll call the manager to let him out once we out of here.
我弄掉了
I dropped some.
我去捡  外婆
I'll get it, Grandma.
那奶酪闻起来真香
That cheese smells awfully good.
看看你逼我干的好事
Look what you made me do.
你以为用偷来的钥匙
You think you're so clever,
闯进我的房间很机智吗
breaking into my room with a stolen key?
但所有人都知道  前台有备用钥匙
But everyone knows they keep a spare key at the front desk.
我们决不会让你恶毒的计划得逞
We'll never let you get away with your filthy, evil plot.
是吗  谁能阻止我
Oh, no? Who's gonna stop me?
你这样软弱愚蠢的女病人吗
A feeble, stupid, sick woman like you?
你觉得这很好笑吗
Oh, you think that's funny?
不是笑这个
Not that.
我只是在想
See, I was just thinking.
很快你就什么都做不了了
Pretty soon, you not gonna be able to do much of nothing.
为什么呢  命不久矣的勇敢小女人
And why is that, brave, little, soon-to-be-dead woman?
豌豆汤
The pea soup.
The pea soup...
不  不
No... No...
不
No...
你个蠢货
You stupid fool.
我没喝豌豆汤
I did not drink the pea soup.
你还记得吗
If you recall,
我被打断了
I was interrupted.
我们这么办
Okay, here's what we're gonna do.
哎呀呀
Well, well, well.
我想想
Let me see.
我要
I think
把手插进你的胸膛
I will reach into your chest
扯出你虚弱
and rip out your withered,
萎缩的心脏
shriveled heart,
然后把它捏爆
and squeeze it until it bursts.
不听不听  王八念经
Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
唬人的女巫腔调根本吓不到我
All your butt-ugly witch-talk don't scare me one bit.
你该害怕的
It should,
毕竟你死前最后看到的
considering the last thing you will ever see
将是我窃笑的脸
is my snickering face.
我
I believe
全身心地相信
with every fiber of my being...
到头来
that in the end,
爱总能战胜仇恨与邪恶
love will always triumph over hatred and evil.
是吗
Is that so?
虽然你转化了爱丽丝和我的外孙
You may have turned Alice and my grandson,
但我会确保你再也没法加害别的孩子
but I will make sure you never turn another child.
帮帮我  上帝
So help me, God.
就现在
Now!
你这愚蠢的老鼠
You stupid rat.
看看你干了什么好事
Look what you've done.
快跑
Run!
看看你干了什么好事
Look what you've done.
你们这群傻耗子
You stupid rodents.
回来
Get back here!
肮脏的害虫
You filthy pests.
-好吃的  -寄生虫
- Yum. - Parasites.
小鬼  我会抓住的
Kid, I'm gonna get you,
你这恶心的害虫
you putrid varmints.
我来抓你了
Now I've got you!
什么
What?
我听够你的鬼话了
I'm done listening to your trash talk.
这是什么
What is this?
蠢货
You fool.
放我出去
Let me out.
Let me out!
放我出去  放我出去
Let me out! Let me out!
我要拔了你们的舌头
I will rip out your tongues.
蠢耗子
Stupid mice.
瓶子里的女巫
The witch in a bottle...
-放我出去  -瓶子里的女巫
- Let me out. - Witch in a bottle...
拿开这蠢鱼缸  让我出去
Let me out of this stupid fish bowl.
外婆  这是那个大箱子的钥匙
Hey, Grandma, this is the key to that big trunk.
那是我的钥匙  那是我的钥匙
That's my key. That's my key.
那是我的钥匙  你这白痴小鬼
That's my key, you pea-brain brat.
-你们这些白痴寄生虫  -来吧  大伙
- You pea-brain parasites. - Come on, guys.
舌头放回嘴里去
Put your tongue back in your mouth,
下水道里的脏东西
you filthy sewer guttersnipes.
你们在干嘛
What are you doing?
那是我的
That is mine.
That's mine.
你们这些白痴  恶棍
You idiots. You scoundrels.
能买好多培根啊
That is a lot of bacon.
-生菜  -面团
- Lettuce. - Dough.
你们说得我好饿
Hey, you're making me terribly hungry.
不  不许碰那个  那是我的
No, get your hands off of that, that's mine!
不许用你们的脏爪碰我的脏钱
Get your filthy paws off my filthy lucre.
我要戳瞎你们的眼睛  你们看什么
I'll poke out your beady eyes. What are you looking at?
那是什么  外婆
What's that, Grandma?
这是世界上所有女巫的
It's a list of names and addresses
姓名和地址清单
of every witch in the world.
这清单  这笔钱  加上这些药水
With that list and that money and all this potion,
我们能把世上所有女巫都变成老鼠
we could turn every witch in the world into rats.
棒极了
Excellent!
我要用生锈的剪刀剪了你们的尾巴
I'll cut off your tails with rusty scissors.
用指甲剪剪掉你们的耳朵
I'll clip your ears with toenail clippers.
我要戳瞎你们的眼睛
I'll poke out your beady eyes.
你们会付出代价的
I'll get you for this!
好了  孩子们  跳进来
All right, kiddies, one hop.
我们有活要干
We got work to do.
我差点忘了
I almost forgot.
不不不  别别别
No, no, no, don't do that.
你要干什么
What are you doing?
哈迪斯
Hades.
好猫咪
Good pussy.
你是只好猫咪
You are a good pussy cat.
乖咪咪
Nice kitty.
-你们俩好好玩  -乖咪咪
- You two have fun now. - Nice kitty.
你这愚蠢生疮流脓的跳蚤窝  宝贝
Ah, you stupid, mangy fleabag. Precious.
把书放回来
Put the books back.
别过来  你这蠢货  宝贝
Stay back, you stupid, precious...
不  哈迪斯
No! Hades.
哈迪斯  宝贝  想想是谁喂的你
Hades, precious, remember who feeds you.
不  别想吃的
No, don't think about food.
外婆  你听到了吗
Grandma, you hear that?
不知道你说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
我什么都没听到
I didn't hear a thing.
真是太谢谢了
Well, thank you kindly.
也给你
And one for you.
第二天
The next morning,
我们欢欣鼓舞  开心不已
we were feeling joyful and triumphant.
实际上  外婆特别开心
As a matter of fact, Grandma was so happy,
把她的喜悦传播给了酒店全体工作人员
she was spreading her joy to the entire hotel staff.
衷心感谢你所做的一切
Thank you kindly for everything.
也给你
One for you.
还有你
And one for you.
谢谢  女士
Thank you, ma'am.
布鲁诺试过向他妈妈解释情况
Bruno tried to explain the situation to his mom.
你好  妈妈
Hello, Mother.
我变成老鼠了
I'm now a mouse.
-老鼠  -但是我们发现
- It's a mouse! - But it turned out
詹金斯夫妇不太喜欢老鼠
Mr. And Mrs. Jenkins weren't really mouse people.
所以我们认为布鲁诺最好
So, we decided it would be best
还是和我  外婆以及黛西一起住
if Bruno came to stay with me, Grandma, and Daisy.
再快点  再快点
Faster, faster!
冲啊
Here we go!
酷
Cool!
我的发型如何  我的发型如何
How's my hair look? How's my hair?
我们再来一次
Let's go again, y'all.
这次我坐前面
This time I sit in the front.
外婆  我喜欢当老鼠
Grandma, I love being a mouse.
这话我相信
Oh, I believe you do.
但你知道奇怪的是什么吗
But you wanna know something weird?
我还是感觉自己是个小男孩
I still feel just like a boy.
但你就是啊  亲爱的
But you are, darling.
生活把我们都改变了
Life changes all of us.
看看我
I mean, look at me.
岁月让我逐渐衰老
I'm getting on up in the years,
但我仍然感觉自己是个小姑娘
but I still feel like a girl.
我也仍然感觉自己是个小男孩
And I still feel like a boy.
看吧
See?
你很明白
You get it.
永远不要放弃自我
Never give up what you are inside.
我看你的时候  我看的不是胡须和粉鼻子
When I look at you, I don't see whiskers and a pink nose.
我看的是你的眼睛
I just see your eyes.
明亮而美丽
Bright and beautiful.
外婆
Grandma,
老鼠能活多久
how long does a mouse live?
普通的老鼠大概能活三年
Oh, an ordinary mouse only lives about three years,
但你不是普通的老鼠  你是人变的老鼠
but you're no ordinary mouse. You're a mouse-person,
人变的老鼠肯定能比普通老鼠
and a mouse-person will almost certainly live
多活三倍的时间
three times longer than an ordinary mouse.
甚至可能更久
Maybe even longer.
这真棒
That's great news.
我可受不了让别人照顾
I couldn't stand being looked after by anybody else.
我会变成一只特别老的老鼠
I'll be a very old mouse
你会变成特别老的外婆
and you'll be a very old grandmother,
然后我们一起死去
and we'll both die together.
也许有可能  亲爱的
With a little luck, darling.
但是谁都不知道自己能活多久
But no one knows how long their time is on this earth.
只有上帝知道
Only God knows that answer.
这是自然规律
And that is the natural order of things.
黛西  布鲁诺和我喜欢和外婆一起生活
Daisy, Bruno, and I loved living with Grandma.
我们是一个快乐的大家庭
We were one big, happy family.
圣诞老鼠快乐
圣诞耗祝福
亚利桑那州
欢迎来到拉斯维加斯
捣蛋还是老鼠
米兰
比萨
佛罗伦萨
罗马
那不勒斯
索伦托
我们整了那群女巫
匿名79
女巫猎手
我们说到哪了  对了
Where were we? Oh, yeah. That's right.
我们到了这里
So, here we are,
准备继续战斗
ready to carry on the fight.
继续战斗
Carry on the fight!
这些年来  我们已经把美国境内
Over the years, we have turned and mouse-afied
每一个该死的女巫都变成了老鼠
every damnable witch in these United States.
我们聚集在此  是要把我们的战斗
So, we are gathered here to take our battle
推广到全世界
to the entire world.
-你们都拿到名单了  对吗  -是  先生
- You have your names, correct? - Yes, sir.
地址呢
Your addresses?
是  先生
Yes, sir.
以及86号变鼠剂
And your Number 86 Mouse Maker potion?
是  先生  86号变鼠剂  先生
Yes, sir. Number 86 Mouse Maker potion, sir.
我们去让
Let's get out there
那群女巫自食恶果
and give those witches a taste of their own medicine.
你准备好执行这次任务了吗  老伙计
So, you ready for this mission, old-timer?
外婆  我时刻准备着
Grandma, I've never been more ready.
罗尔德·达尔
女巫